<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Stephen D. O&#39;Connell</title>
    <link>/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Stephen D. O&#39;Connell</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Targeting unconditional cash transfers to Syrian refugees in Lebanon</title>
      <link>/project/targeting/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/targeting/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In collaboration with UNHCR and UN-WFP, my team (Onur Altındağ, Bentley University; Aytug Sasmaz, Harvard University; Zeynep Balcioglu, Northeastern University) and I have designed the targeting system for over USD300 million of annual unconditional cash and in-kind assistance to Syrian refugees in Lebanon. A manuscript about this work is available in &lt;a href=&#34;../../publication/aosb2019/&#34;&gt;research&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flipping &#39;Metrics</title>
      <link>/project/flippingmetrics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/flippingmetrics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;During graduate school, I taught Econometrics to 10 sections of over 300 undergraduate students over three years at Hunter College, CUNY (present in my first class ever was the notable &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.twitter.com/yfeyman&#34;&gt;@yfeyman&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Training in Econometrics, in my view and experience, is possibly &lt;em&gt;the&lt;/em&gt; defining aspect of an Economics major sought by companies, research organizations, and non-profits who hire Economics majors. I enjoy teaching a mix of theoretical and mathematical rigor as well as practical application using real-world data and programming in statistical software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this project, funded by Emory University&amp;rsquo;s Center for Faculty Development and Excellence, I will combine and integrate multiple ongoing innovations in the teaching of Econometrics to develop and house a set of online materials that can be used to teach a “flipped” class of undergraduate Econometrics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This “flipped classroom” will comprise a set of materials that include:
-   Recorded video lectures,
-   Examples and practice learning materials built in R/RMarkdown that students can download and learn both principles and applications, primarily centered around real-world data and examples,
-   Lecture and teaching materials from the newly-added “lab” component of the Statistics &amp;amp; Econometrics sequence which teaches students the foundational programming tools for statistical and econometric analysis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The project has a second component: connecting to professional application. This segment will invite non-academic professionals who use econometrics in practice to speak to students about their training, experience, and overall career paths.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Timeline: in development, beta completed by summer, 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
